Contact

fnozoy@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/fabio-nozoy-4b338235 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

SQL

Java

Spring Boot

Languages

Spanish (Professional Working)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)

Certifications

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

Six Sigma Green Belt

Fabio Nozoy

Dev Lead | Java | Spring Boot | SQL | Cloud | CI/CD São Bernardo do Campo

Summary

28 years in Systems Development working with Customer Services, Sales & Marketing and Manufacturing business areas. 18y most recent years in solutions with Java Web applications and 10 years back with Cobol in mainframe and Unix.

Strong skills to solve business needs, lead development teams in the whole lifecycle of an application, from the inception to software delivery and maintenance.

Used to communicate with all levels of the company in different country locations, conduct simultaneous projects and play different roles such as project manager, developer, scrum master, product owner, tester, DBA, etc...

Have good tech skills related to daily activity with Java mostly on backend, Spring Boot, integration and functional tests, Oracle, SQL server, DB2, Git, CA Agile

Other abilities by implementing cloud native applications on PCF (Pivotal Cloud Foundry), continuous integration CI/CD, unit tests, Cobol environment and Teradata.

I speak Portuguese, English and Spanish.

Bachelor degree in Mathematics with emphasis in Computing and post-graduation in Project Management.

Ability to continuously learn new techs. I recently got the "IBM certificate in Data Science" that covers Python, Web Scrapping, SQL and Machine Learning. I also recently acquired some skills in React-JS and PostgreSQL (projects available on my GitHub).

I live in São Bernardo do Campo, in the state of São Paulo, Brazil (GMT -3).

Married and happy, we have a lovely teenager daughter.

I dedicate myself to learn new technologies and different cultures.

Visit my portfolio on GitHub https://github.com/fnozoy/

Experience

Ford Motor Company 25 years 10 months

Senior Dev Lead June 2018 - Present (3 years 4 months)

São Bernardo do Campo, São Paulo, Brasil

Head of IT Warranty Squad in South America, assumed the group to develop a project of US\$ 1 million plus.

Coordinated 7 people in the dev team for 2 years, with the team splited in Brazil and Argentina. Managed adversities like 2 cost reductions and high team turnover, forcing to negotiate project scope with small harm for the project delivery date.

Developed a new application using technologies like:

Java, Spring, Oracle, Cloud Environment (PCF), Angular, GitHub, etc This is a transactional application, it exposes and consume many APIs. This app alone will payback the investment in 2 or 3 years

Also managed 4 Legacy apps such an Oracle DataWarehouse, a ASP Classic and other 4 in Mainframe, that were migrated to Cloud environment bringing more competitive costs to keep it.

Additionally we managed the implementation of a Ford Global application of Warranty in South America that is the most disrruptive change in Warranty process in the last 20 years. I was responsible to coordinate 7 Software Houses in Brazil that attend Ford Distributors, it was a big effort and consummed many technical and management time. It was all coordinates in conjunction with Ford US manage team, that was partially in US and India.

IT Senior Project Coordinator in IT Shared Services June 2017 - May 2018 (1 year)

São Bernardo do Campo, São Paulo, Brasil

Coordinator for Technology Renew of 100+ applications in South America.

This project demanded technology guidance for obsolete technologies, which as key to move all applications to Cloud environment.

Additionally I was responsible for guidance and approval of technologies to be used in new applications acting also as local architect in conjunction with Global architecture team.

Dev Lead in Direct Sales

June 2012 - May 2017 (5 years)

São Bernardo do Campo, São Paulo, Brasil

Head of IT Direct Sales projects.

Coordinated a team of 2 \sim 5 developers. The team was responsible for: .Brazil Direct Sales of Vehicles to fleet customers application (Java, Struts 1.3, Oracle), that represented 20%+ of all sales in Brazil. It has a complex algorith to balance Discount and Comission, and invoke the approval chain when applied

.Develop new application portal for Employee Direct Sales of Brazil and Argentina (Java, JSF, Struts, Oracle). It allowed Ford Employees to buy a car according to Ford policy with discount over the public price. It was implemented first in Brazil and after Argentina. This employee portal beated even the best distributor in number of sales.

Project Coordinator - New app for dealer parts inventory control May 2005 - June 2012 (7 years 2 months)

Coordinator for Dealer Inventory Control Lead a team of 4 developers. App developed in Java, SQL Server and Struts

Implemented in Mexico, Brazil and Argentina

On phase 1, it had the premisse to determine what was the parts with high, medium and low flow in the dealer inventory, it also determine obsolete parts that had never been sold in 'X' time. After the classification and based on the last demands, the app suggested the order for the dealer with more volume in the high flow parts and etc...

On phase 2, it helped the dealers to find parts in other dealers and puting them in contact to trade.

Key objective was to reduce parts obsolete, low and medium flow in the dealers inventory. It allows the dealers to get rid of unnecessary inventory and gain some cash for more important things like local marketing campains.

Systems Analyst
December 1995 - May 2005 (9 years 6 months)
.Sales and Marketing Systems Analysts

Worked with mainframe Cobol, DB2, IMS/DC applications

Responsible to maintain the Ordering application of Ford Brazil and Argentina Developed and entire new algorith to solve the distribution of vehicles among dealers, by making the

vehicles dispatch more linear based on month program by model, optionals and color.

.Manufacturing and Plant Floor Systems Analyst

Worked with mainframe Cobol, DB2, IMS/DB, IMS/DC applications Responsible to maintain the production control application of Ford Argentina and 2 plants of Brazil

Developed the month program by model, optionals and color for logistics

Banco Itaú Mainframe Developer - Cobol, DB2, JCL, TSO 1993 - 1995 (2 years) São Paulo e Região, Brasil

Education

Centro Universitário Fundação Santo André

Mathematics Bachelor Degree with emphasis in Computing (1989 - 1993)

Fundação Getulio Vargas / FGV

Post-Graduation in Project Management · (2010 - 2011)

FIAP

Post-Graduation in Object Oriented projects with Java · (2006 - 2006)

Universidade de São Paulo

Post-Graduation in Information Technology (2002 - 2003)

Etec Lauro Gomes

Electronics Technician · (1986 - 1988)